Javier Resto - Delgado

San Antonio, TX • (787) 247-5089 • j.resto.delgado@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic, driven and dedicated individual, conscious of the world around him and eager to begin a new structured career in Hospitality and Customer Service, in which I over 14 years of experience. I am a focused and resourceful problem solver with a highly organized approach. I am sharp employee who promotes the use of common sense in the work place. I consider myself both confident and competent in a variety of both working and social situations and pride myself on being a professional, reliable and loyal individual.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AREA SALES MANAGER

July 2018 - Present

ALDO Shoes | San Antonio TX, San Marcos TX, Austin TX

- ➤ Work directly with the District Manager to ensure the stores in the district achive sales goals and deliver exceptional customer service.
- ► Help recruiting, training and developing Assistant Managers and Store Managers across the district as well as ensuring exceptional training is given to every new staff member.
- ► Required to perform seasonal Store Inventories and analyze results across the area.
- ► Responsible for performing Visual Merchandising visits to ensure that visual presentation guidelines are met.
- ► Perform Loss Prevention sessions across the district to ensure and enforce loss prevention and security policies.
- ► Manage payroll and scheduling in the district to ensure payroll budget is met weekly.
- > Follows up on customer complaints across the district by contacting them directly and providing them with options and solutions to ensure customer satisfaction is met.
- Hold Store Managers accountable to the budget set to them for the week and provide course correcting options when goals are not met.
- ➤ Conduct Performance Evaluations.

AREA SALES MANAGER

August 2016 - July 2018

ALDO Shoes | Tucson AZ, Phoenix AZ

- ➤ Work directly with the District Manager to ensure the stores in the district achive sales goals and deliver exceptional customer service.
- ► Help recruiting, training and developing Assistant Managers and Store Managers across the district as well as ensuring exceptional training is given to every new staff member.
- ► Required to perform seasonal Store Inventories and analyze results across the area.
- ► Responsible for performing Visual Merchandising visits to ensure that visual presentation guidelines are met.
- ► Perform Loss Prevention sessions across the district to ensure and enforce loss prevention and security policies.
- ► Manage payroll and scheduling in the district to ensure payroll budget is met weekly.
- ► Follows up on customer complaints across the district by contacting them directly and providing them with options and solutions to ensure customer satisfaction is met.
- ► Hold Store Managers accountable to the budget set to them for the week and provide course correcting options when goals are not met.
- Conduct Performance Evaluations.

ALDO Shoes | Puerto Rico

- ► Recruited qualified, professional people and communicated all pertinent information to payroll
- ► Provided ongoing training and regular performance-based feedback to all team members.
- ► Ensured all team members comply with company policies, procedure, and brand initiatives through training and communication.
- ► Responsible for leading the store team to achieve company goals and personal sales objectives daily.
- Ensured the store is brand-aligned through flawless execution of visual presentation and marketing display.
- ► Implemented, adhere and enforce the loss prevention and security policies for the store.
- ► Managed the store within store operations budget (salary, inventory, expenses and payroll.)
- ➤ Created a diverse and inclusive atmosphere free from discrimination and harassment, reflective of our People-First philosophy.

ASSISTANT STORE MANAGER

August 2011 - November 2013

ALDO Shoes | Puerto Rico

- Supported the Store Manager in building a fashion-centric team of collaborative and engaged talent through recruiting and networking.
- ► Provided ongoing training and regular performance-based feedback to all team members.
- ➤ Maximized personal and store sales by promoting brand initiatives and delivering a "customer-obsessed" omnichannel experience.
- ► Ensured all team members comply with company policies and procedures.
- ➤ Assisted in controlling operational costs through payroll and asset management.

BAR MANAGER

February 2009 – March 2011

Cutting Edge Bar Group: The Edge | London UK

- ➤ Being a flexible worker was a fundamental pre-requisite of working for this group as I was often called upon to cover stores in which I had no previous experience.
- Although ultimately answering to the general manager, I was responsible for all tasks within the store, from opening, through close. My main responsibly was to ensure the constant and steady increase in sales which was vital to the new venture.
- ► Ensured all team members comply with company policies, procedure, and brand initiatives through training and communication.
- Managed the store within store operations budget (salary, inventory, expenses and payroll.)
- ➤ Carried out, on a daily basis, all mandatory and routine operations expected within a popular store, in central London, including till floats, cash ups, change orders and collection, banking and stock maintenance. Attended to basic wine training courses whilst employed at this establishment.

Additional SKILLS

- •Strong sense of competency with most computer-based systems including tills, alarms, security cameras and sound tech, stemming from my university education.
- Personal appreciation of the diversity of the world enables me to relate to a great variety of people. This along with a friendly and proactive demeanor allows me to establish relationships with confidence and ease. I am bilingual and proficient in both Spanish and English.
- Willing to learn, self-reliant, focused and resourceful with the ability to prioritize and the self-assurance to make decisions in order to complete tasks.
- •Strict organization, time management skills and capability of multi-tasking, I am able to work to meet tight deadlines efficiently.
- •I am a diligent team worker, able to communicate ideas effectively, adapting oral and report writing skills with well-practiced presentation techniques

EDUCATION